KEVIN GIORGIO TOLEDO DE LA CRUZ - SR SOLUTION ARCHITECT

SUMMARY

He has 5 years of experience as a solution architect working with Cloud and DevOps/automation projects for different clients. I have worked with different cloud providers (AWS, Oracle, Azure, GCP) and tools/languages like Python, Java, JavaScript, Terraform, Ansible, Jenkins, Git, Bitbucket, Kubernetes, Docker. I have been a Cloud/Solution Architect, Cloud Engineer, DevOps Engineer and Customer Success Engineer in different IT companies.

SKILLS

- Kubernetes
- Amazon Cloudwatch
- Amazon EC2
- Amazon VPC
- Amazon Web Services
- Automation Using Scripting and Programming Languages
- AWS CloudFormation
- AWS Lambda
- AWS ApiGateway
- Bash
- Cloud Operations
- DevOps
- Docker
- Git
- Identity and Access Management
- Python
- Azure DevOps
- GCP

- Terraform
- Ansible
- CI/CD
- Database Configuration and Maintenance
- Information Technology Infrastructure Library
- Jenkins
- Linux
- Linux Containers
- OS Administration
- Troubleshooting
- UNIX shell scripting
- AWS Cloud Development Kit
- Helm
- Azure Cloud
- Vagrant
- Oracle Cloud
- Unix Administration

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apr. 2022 - Current Cloud Engineer - Globant

Project: MiNIssanApp is a mobile application where the customers get information about their Nissan Cars. This app is available in Mexico.

Team size: 3 PM, 1 Tech Lead, 4 Team Lead, 15 Developers, 1 Cloud Engineer, 1 DevOps Tasks performed:

- Implement the infrastructure in AWS that supports Backend code. 5 AWS accounts managed using IaC.
- Maintain good performance metrics in the Production environment. Have a meeting weekly
 with the Architecture Board to review the metrics and the correction plan. Accomplish reduce
 response time of app doing refactor of code using the best practices for AWS Lambda functions
 and AWS Elasticache with average of 3 seconds as result.
- Create cloud solution architecture to front big issues of the projects using Serverless Architectures and Event Driven Architecture. Design and Implement new features for the appusing AWS ECS/EKS Fargate and Api Gateway following microservice pattern.

•

Tools: CDK, CloudFormation, AWS Api Gateway, AWS Lambda Function, AWS RDS Aurora Postgresql, AWS Step Functions, Python, Bash, AWS DynamoDB, AWS ECS/EKS, Fargate, AWS CloudWatch X-Ray, AWS EventBridge, AWS ELB, AWS EC2, Jenkins, Github, Helm, Bitbucket, Terraform, AWS ECR, AWS S3, AWS WAF, AWS CloudFront, Node.js, Typescript, Java, VPC, Docker, CI/CD.

Jan, 2022 - Mar, 2022 DevOps Engineer - Banco de Bogotá

Project: Security App for authenticating the users using the personal and financial information.

Team size: 1 Scrum Master, 6 Developers, 3 QA Engineer, 1 DevOps (Small Dev Pod)

Tasks performed:

- Implement CI/CD with GitHub Actions to deliver software and infrastructure as code in AWS Accounts. Maintain different environments including Prod environment. Deploy new features and hotfixes is Prod environment weekly.
- Participate in different activities using Agile methodology like daily meeting, sprint planning and retrospective meeting, to deliver software more faster.
- Lead migration of AWS ECS Containers to AWS EKS Project. Also, accomplish migration of infrastructure to IaC using Terraform with 3 (Dev, Stg, Prod) environments in AWS Accounts with the same code as result.

Tools: Terraform, Github Actions, Docker, AWS ECR, AWS ECS, AWS EKS, AWS Lambda, AWS Api Gateway, AWS S3, AWS CloudFront, AWS WAF, Python, Node.js, Java, Prometheus, Grafana, AWS CodeDeploy, Helm, VPC, Docker, Ansible.

Nov, 2020 - Jan, 2022 Cloud Solution Engineer - Oracle

Project: Design and Implement Cloud Solution.

Team size: 1 Manager, 10 Cloud Engineer

Tasks performed:

- Design cloud architectures to solve problems for different customers in LATAM. Create demos and PoC to show new features of cloud services. Develop comparison between AWS/GCP/Azure and Oracle Cloud.
- Implement cloud architectures and Accomplish cloud migrations using Oracle Cloud from AWS/GCP/Azure with 5 projects as result.
- Lead technical campaigns to improve the experience of cloud customers. Accomplish the growth of cloud consumption using technical meetings with average 2.5% week over week as result. Accomplish webinar about DevOps in OCI using Oracle DevOps Service.

Tools: Terraform, Oracle Instances, Linux, Windows, Nodejs, Oracle Database, AWS EC2, MySQL, Oracle DevOps Service, Jenkins, Azure DevOps, Docker, Ansible, Bash, Unix Administration, CI/CD, Kubernetes, Microservices.

<u>Month, Year - Month, Year</u> System Service Representative - Company

Project: Support to maintain Bank application available.

Team size: 1 Technical Manager, 24 System Engineers

Tasks performed:

- Manage different services running in WebSphere for a big bank in Colombia. Create a plan for Linux and AIX administration. Implement patches in Prod environment using Ticket process and
- Create CI/CD pipeline to provision Java Application inside Websphere application Server.
- Develop automation using Python to maintain the WebSphere services. Implement maintenance tasks using Ansible as configuration management tool.
- Lead an automation project that consists in extracting the status of applications running into Websphere with the goal using Python with status reports file .xls as result.
- Collaborate in a migration project from On-Premises servers to AWS cloud using Terraform and Azure DevOps.

Tools: Linux, Windows, AIX, Azure DevOps, Terraform, AWS EC2, AWS ECS/EKS, AWS Lambda, AWS Api Gateway, Python, Websphere Application Server.

Feb. 2020 - Mar. 2020 Developer I - Tekbees

Project: Facial Recognition App

Team size: 1 Project Manager, 6 Developer

Tasks performed:

- Collaborate with new functionalities in backend side using Node.JS, Javascript and MongoDB as Non-Relational Database
- Develop microservices with Python for AI services and containerize the app using Docker Engine to deploy it in local Linux systems to test. Deploy in prod environment into GCP and AWS.
- Collaborate with creation of frontend side using Angular and Vue.js and deploy it into S3 Bucket as Static Content.

Tools: Linux, Docker, Python, Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, GCP, AWS S3, AWS EC2.

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019 Developer - GITEI

Project: Creation of Digital Content for Education Ministry

Team size: 4 Developers, 3 Graphic Designers 1 Scrum Master, 1 Tech Lead, 1 Project Manager Tasks performed:

- Collaborate with the development of educational projects. Implement the development using Ionic to create hybrid mobile apps.
- Participate in technical meetings with the ministry people to teach about technologies that the group is using web pages.

3

Implement the uploading of courses designed inside the group into the educational platform.

Tools: Wordpress, Angular, Linux, Ubuntu, AWS EC2.

Aug, 2018 - Aug, 2019 Cloud Architect Jr - IBM

Project: Design and implement cloud solutions in IBM Cloud

Team size: 1 Tech Manager, 6 Presales Consultant, 3 Cloud Architects.

Tasks performed:

- Create Cloud Architecture that solves problems for different customers with IBM Cloud and AWS. Accomplish IaC delivery using Terraform with 5 solution packages as result.
- Lead an architecture design for a project with Digital Solution Client in Colombia. Design and implement demos and PoC using IBM and AWS services. Train customers in Cloud Topic and DevOps methodology.
- Collaborate in the migration to IBM Cloud of a big customer as solution architect and delivery consultant.
- Achieve Special Mention in Innovation and Outstanding Student.

Tools: Node.js, DevOps Toolchain, Jenkins, IBM Virtual Instances, AWS VPC, AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS Block Storage, AWS Lambdas, Github Actions.

EDUCATION

- MSc in Cybersecurity IMF In progress.
- Bachelor in Electrical Engineering National University of Colombia.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified in AWS Cloud Practitioner.
- Certified in AWS Solution Architect Associate.
- Certified in AWS Developer Associate.
- Certified in Oracle Cloud Architect